I remember the magic spell
From back when a rainbow stretched across the sky
In an instant, every corner of the world
Took on a brilliant hue
The voice of my heart
Always illuminates the path I need to take
It is because I doubt everything
That I know it to be true
Why does my heart still beat?
Why do my lungs still breathe?
Why is my chest burning with passion?
There's a reason for all of that
And, like the starry sky hidden behind the clouds
Like the ticket to a destination I lost somewhere
Like the history of the world from before I was born
You hold the answer just beyond my reach
If nothing else, I know that all too well
If nobody else, I know that all too well
Something Given (Part 1)
（桐山(きりやま) 零(れい)）あ
12月
December.
When Christmas was approaching,
クリスマスが近くなったころ—
姉 香子(きょうこ)から再び電話が来た
I got another call from my foster sister, Kyouko.
You forgot something?
忘れ物？ 時計？
A watch?
あ　あった
Here it is.
Thank goodness.
（幸田(こうだ)香子(きょうこ)）よかった
Gotou just gave it to me.
もらったばかりなのよ 後藤(ごとう)に
してないと怒られちゃう
He gets mad if I don't wear it.
ハクシュ！
Hey, I might've gotten a cold.
ちょっと 風邪引いたかも
And it's your fault!
あんたのせいよ
I told you to wait at the Mec in front of the station.
だから
駅前のメックで待っててって…
No way. That place is way too noisy.
嫌よ あんな騒がしいとこ
Why couldn't I have gone to your place?
何で あんたんちじゃ駄目なのよ
"Why"?
何でって…
How about I guess what you were just thinking, Rei?
今 何考えたか
当ててあげようか？ 零
ウフッ
冗談よ　怖い顔
I'm just joking. No need for the scary face.
Hey, what are you doing for New Year's?
ねえ 年末はどうするの？
You're coming home, right?
帰ってくるんでしょ？
No.
いや
対局が結構 詰まってるし
I have a lot of matches coming up,
so I need to focus on practicing.
勉強しないといけないから
（香子）対局？
Matches?
Your last match of the year is the class-promotion one against Yasui on the 24th, right?
あんたの今年の対局は
24日の安井(やすい)さんとの順位戦で
ラストでしょう？
Oh, that's right.
あ そうそう 安井さんといえば
Speaking of Yasui, it seems he's finally getting divorced.
ついに 離婚 決まったらしいわね
He's usually a modest, meek guy.
普段は 腰が低くて気も弱いのに
But when he loses, he drinks, gets crazy, and gambles.
負けると 飲んで暴れて
ギャンブルでしょう？
I'm surprised his wife put up with it for this long.
奥さんも 今までよく我慢したわよ
I feel sorry for his daughter the most.
かわいそうなのは娘さんよね
She must've been scared.
怖かったでしょうね
I mean, since she was living under the same roof
with a father who breaks bad every time he loses.
負ける度に
別人になっちゃうお父さんと
同じ屋根の下だったわけでしょう？
I hate this.
（零）ああ 嫌だ
But I hear the daughter had one wish.
（香子）でもね
娘さんが言ったんですって
クリスマスまでは
パパと一緒にいたいって
She said, "I wanna be with Daddy until Christmas."
（零）たまらなく嫌だ
I can't stand this...
この…
Doesn't it just brings tears to your eyes?
泣かせるわよね
そう思わない？
The way she speaks, her words sticking to me like glue...
（零）
べったりと張り付くような
姉の物言いが
ねえ 零　聞いてる？
Hey, are you listening?
But more than anything...
（零）何より…
Hey.
ちょっと…
...her words that drip with poison...
（零）
こんな 毒をはらんだ言葉ですら
Sheesh.
Your scarf will blow away.
マフラー飛んじゃうわよ
You should wrap it properly.
巻くなら ちゃんと巻きなさいよ
I hate myself for wanting to hear them.
（零）聞いていたいと思う自分が
Children have it rough.
（香子）子供ってかわいそうよね
After all, they can't choose their parents.
だって
親を選ぶことはできないもの
ああ でもそうね
Though, come to think of it, that doesn't apply to you.
あなたは違ったっけね
You chose your own parents.
自分で親を選んだんだものね
他人の家の父親をね
You chose somebody else's father.
（子供たち）
わあっ　アハハ…
Hey, Dad, can we open them now?
（香子）
ねえ お父さん　もう開けていい？
Oh, sure.
（幸田(こうだ)柾近(まさちか)）ああ いいぞ
Hey, what is this giant teddy bear?!
ちょっと 何よ？ このでかクマ
Pow
Take that
Hmph
Pow
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
Hmph
Pow
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
もう お父さんたら
私 もう中学生なのよ
Take that
Pow
Jeez, Dad! I'm in junior high now!
Take that
Hmph
Hm
ph
Take that
Pow
Hm
ph
Take that
Hmph
Hm
ph
Take that
Pow
Hm
ph
Take that
Pow
Hmph
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
Pow
Hmph
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
Pow
Hmph
Hm
ph
Take that
Hm
ph
Take that
（幸田(こうだ) 歩(あゆむ)）お〜 ゲームボムだ
A Game Bomb!
（零）ハア…
For a child of this family,
（零の声）この家の子なら…
or anyone striving to be a professional shogi player,
棋士を目指す人間なら
その美しい駒の持つ
価値が 意味が—
the value of those beautiful pieces,
their meaning, and the father's feelings...
父の胸の内が
分からないはずがなかった
were unmistakable.
どうだ？ 零
What do you think, Rei?
Should I have gotten you a toy too?
お前も おもちゃとかの方が
よかったかな？
いえ
Oh, no.
あ… ありがとうございます
Th-Thank you.
I'm happy with these.
すっごくうれしいです
It was unmistakable.
（零の声）
分からないはずがなかった
姉が 弟が
そのとき どんなに傷ついたかも
How my foster brother and sister were very hurt then.
Hey, don't you think it's sad?
（香子）ねえ 切ないわね
A daddy who comes home after winning, or a daddy who comes home after losing.
勝って帰ってきたパパと
負けて帰ってきたパパ
Now then...
さあ
which would be more fitting as a final Christmas memory?
最後のクリスマスの思い出に
ぴったりなのは どっちかしら？
（林田(はやしだ)高志(たかし)）うーん
体育と音楽以外は まあまあかな
Aside from P.E. and music, not bad, I guess.
Your grades for math and physics are awesome.
つーか 数学と物理とか すげえいい
Report Card
てなわけで ほい
That being said, here.
９時30分までに千駄ヶ谷だろ？
You need to be in Sendagaya by 9:30, right?
You'd better hurry.
急がないと
しっかし 忙しいな お前も
Anyway, you're a busy guy, aren't you?
You even have matches up until the closing ceremony.
終業式まで対局とは
You barely met the required attendance days this time,
出席日数は ギリ足りてるけど
but you may be in trouble if you have more matches in the third trimester.
３学期 これ以上
対局増えるとやばいかも
So be careful.
気を付けてね　フフフフ
What?!
Are you telling me to lose?
負けろと？
But my living is on the line.
いえ あの 生活かかってるんで
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
500 yen for drinks
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
500 yen for drinks
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
500 yen for drinks
1000 yen for present swapping
Class 1-B Christmas Party
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
In Tanaka's
garage
at 5 P.M.
500 yen for drinks
1000 yen for present swapping
By the way, after the closing ceremony today,
the kids in class are apparently having a Christmas party.
ところで 今日終業式終わったら
うちのクラスのやつら
クリスマス会とか
やるらしいんだけど
Did you know?
お前 知ってた？
No, of course I didn't know about it.
ええ 聞いてませんとも　もちろん
Please don't inform me.
教えないでくださいよっ
Well, I guess there's only one thing to do.
まっ こうなったらしかたねえな
After your match is over, why don't you come back here?
お前さ 対局終わったら
戻ってこねえ？
Dammit, they
didn't invite
me either.
Why?!
Dammit, they
didn't invite
me either.
Why?!
Just us crummy guys, eating cake while playing shogi...
男２人で むさくるしく
ケーキ食いながら
Answer:
You're a teacher.
将棋でも…
Answer:
You're a teacher.
Hey!
って！
No one.
振り返ったら もういねえし
I turn around and he's gone!
キャー　ちょっと待ってよ
Eek!
Wait a second! This just makes me a mean old teacher!
これじゃ オレ
ただの意地悪教師じゃん
Eek!
Oh no!
Will you please listen until I'm done talking, Kiriyama?!
話は最後まで聞こうよ
ねえ 桐山〜
When did it start?
（零）いつごろからだろう
When did Christmas become painful for me?
クリスマスを
苦しいと思うようになったのは
A certain thought crossed my mind.
あるとき ふと思ったのだ
通知表みたいだと
"It's like a report card."
その１年間の
One from that year.
In that year, how much love did I receive from my friends, family, and parents?
この１年間—
友達に 家族に 親に—
どれだけ愛されたか
How did they express that love for me?
どんなふうに愛されていたのか
（零）安井６段
Yasui, 6-dan...
The doors are closing.
（アナウンス）
ドアが閉まります
Please take care.
ご注意ください
The daughter said, "I wanna be with Daddy until Christmas."
（香子）でも娘さんが
せめてクリスマスまでは
一緒にいたいって
言ったんですって
せめてクリスマスまでは…
"Until Christmas."
A daddy who comes home after winning,
（香子）
勝って帰ってきたお父さんと
負けて帰ってきたお父さん
or a daddy who comes home after losing.
Which would be more fitting as a final Christmas memory?
最後のクリスマスの思い出に
ぴったりなのは どっちかしら？
Well,
ねえ？ 零
Rei?
Something Given (Part 1)
Shogi Hall
It's time.
（記録係１）時間になりました
（記録係２）時間になりました
（記録係たち）時間になりました
Let's have a good match.
（零･安井(やすい) 学(まなぶ)）
よろしくお願いします
（棋士たち）よろしくお願いします
The calm mind
is the way
I lost.
（安井）負けました
Something Given (Part 2)
分かったよ
I get it.
You want to say I gave up in the middle of the match, don't you?
要するに 君は
俺が途中で投げたって
言いたいんだろ？
Huh?
安井さんとの対局は 夕方を前に
あっけなく終わりを迎えた
The match with Yasui ended all too soon that late afternoon.
After P-8f, I could've surprised you, taking your knight at 9e...
（安井）
８六歩から嫌味をつけて
９五に桂(けい)を打って…
Ah, yes, yes.
確かにそうだね
I could've gone that way.
気が付いたら 絶対指してたね
If I'd noticed, I would have.
But I didn't notice, so that's that, right?
でもなぁ
気が付かなかったんだもん
しょうがないよね
そりゃあ 君には
分かったのかもしれないけどさ
You might've seen it, but I didn't see it, so what good is it?
俺には 分かんなかったんだから
しかたないだろ
Yasui continued muttering, as if he was talking to himself.
（零）
独り言のように つぶやき続ける
安井さんのため息に
I was unsettled by the faint smell of alcohol on his breath as he sighed.
かすかに混ざる
アルコールの匂いが
僕の胸をざわつかせた
The match began slowly and quietly with a Yagura Opening.
序盤は 矢倉の駒組みで
静かにゆっくり始まった
"Carefully... Carefully..."
慎重に 慎重に
From the way he played,
I could almost hear him telling that to himself.
言い聞かせる声が聞こえるような
指し方だった
ミスするな
"Don't make a mistake."
Shogi
Hall
However,
（零）しかし 昼食休憩の後—
after the lunch break, Yasui made a mistake.
安井さんに ミスが出た
After a short pause, he noticed it too.
（零）
一呼吸遅れて 安井さんも気付いた
いや でもこの先 ８六歩から
玉頭を攻められたら分からない
But if next he had pressured my king with P-8f,
who knows what would've happened?
そして馬を引かれて ねばられたら
勝敗はどちらに傾くか…
If he then pulled his knight back and held out, which side would victory have tilted toward?
But then I could see Yasui's silhouette lose strength and weaken.
と そのとき—
安井さんの輪郭が
力を失って緩んでいくのが見えた
Why?
何で？
It's not...
まだ… まだ 道は全て
消えたわけじゃないのに
It's not like all his paths to victory have been cut off.
I hear the daughter had one wish.
（香子）
娘さんが言ったんですって
Wait a second!
（零）ちょっと待って　何で？
Why?
Why?!
どうして？
You're giving up that easily?
そんな簡単に 手放しちゃ駄目だ
You can't let go! Your focus, your awareness...
集中を 意識を…
せめてクリスマスまでは…
"I wanna be with Daddy...
Don't give up those precious things so easily!
（零）大切なものを
こんな たやすく…
...until Christmas."
一緒にいたいって
Please...
（零）どうか 頼むから
I'm begging you!
手放さないでくれよ
Don't let go!
Shogi
Hall
I lost.
負けました
感想戦も
この辺で もういいだろう
I think that's enough for a post-match review.
I've had enough for today.
今日は ここいらで勘弁してくれ
ハァ　ハァ…
Yasui!
（零）安井さん？　安井さん？
He's gone.
いない　どっちだ
Which way did he go?
は…　いた！　安井さん
There he is!
Where's he going?
どこへ行くんだ？
The station isn't that way.
そっちは駅じゃないのに
ハア　ハア　安井さん！
Yasui!
あの これ…
Um... here.
ハァ　ハァ…
That ain't mine.
俺んじゃない
Never seen it.
知らん
安井さん！
Yasui!
分かったよ！ うるさいなぁ！
All right! Shut up, already!
は〜あ
最後のクリスマスだったのになぁ
And this was our last Christmas...
クッ　フンッ！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
ハア　ハア　ハア
ハア　ゲホッ　ゲホッ
ハア　ハア　ハア…
Is everything my fault?!
みんなオレのせいかよ！
Then what should I have done instead?!
じゃあ
どうすりゃよかったんだよ！
Go to hell!
ふざけんなよ！
It's your own fault for being bad!
弱いのが悪いんじゃんか
弱いから負けんだよ！
You lost because you suck!
Practice!
勉強しろよ！
I can tell when you don't!
してねえの分かんだよ
If you say, "I know, but I can't," then just quit!
分かってるけどできねえとか
言うんならやめろよ！
Don't come!
来んな！
For me, everything's on the line!
こっちは全部懸けてんだよ！
Because I don't have anything else!
他には何も持てねーぐらい
All I have is shogi!
将棋ばっかりだよ！
酒飲んで 逃げてんじゃねえよ
Don't drink booze to escape!
I have no use for shitty players!
弱いやつには 用はねえんだよ！
If you're going to run away...
逃げるなら…
If you can run away...
逃げられるくらいなら…
then why even...
何で…
I said I had no reason to fight,
戦う理由がないと言いながら
but the truth is,
本当は 身の内に
獣が住むのを知っている
I know that a beast lives within me.
It's a rampaging beast that'd bite off everything in sight to survive.
周りのものを食いちぎってでも
生きていくためだけに 走り出す獣
When the battle begins, no matter what,
戦いが始まれば どうしても
生きる道へと手が伸びてしまう
its hand reaches out for the path to survival.
Even if it means misery for others.
誰を不幸にしても
No matter what kind of world awaits.
どんな世界が待っていても
Something Given (Part 2)
Like a resplendent meteor shower
Your words enter my ears and catch fire
They come together like a school of fish
And form a warm corner in my once chilly bosom
As I stood in place, not knowing the right way to reach out
Your hand reached out to touch mine
And no matter how many nights may pass
That warmth still lingers and pulses within
Your very presence shines a bright light on every part of my life
Your racing heartbeat resonates with my frozen heart and sets it ablaze
Before long, the fire dies out
Leaving just one smoldering ember
Which remains with me and won't ever go away
Living inside of me in a place closest to my heart
Next Episode Preview
Episode 11
Yay! Rei's house!
（川本(かわもと)モモ）
わーい　零ちゃんちだ〜
Here, Rei.
（川本(かわもと)ひなた）はい　零ちゃん
首 うーってして？
Stretch out your neck.
Rei?
（幸田）
零？ 零なのか？
Rei, is that you?
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
I'm an idiot.
（零）僕は バカだ
You've got it wrong.
（川本(かわもと)あかり）違うわ
私が来てほしかったの
I wanted you to come over.
You're the one who helped me.
助かったのは 私なのよ
Illustration: Katsu Aki
Don't miss the next episode of
"March comes in like a lion."
（林田）３月のライオン
次回もお楽しみに
I hope everyone watches our great performances!
みんな　俺と桐山の活躍
しっかり見てくれよな
M-Mr. Hayashida...
（零）せ… 先生…